<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cherry's Blog</title><link>//localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content on Cherry's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:28:05 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trying to Review the Lux Music Album by Rosalia</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/trying-to-review-the-lux-music-album-by-rosalia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 08:28:05 -0300</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/trying-to-review-the-lux-music-album-by-rosalia/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: If you found this post randomly, this isn&amp;rsquo;t an analysis nor a review coming from a music expert, it&amp;rsquo;s just my opinions as someone that like different genres and is trying to write more to practice English (and leave doomscrolling). Enjoy and feel free to reach me out if you want :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-thoughts-on-the-whole-album"&gt;My thoughts on the whole album&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading this album for about 2 weeks now, and it&amp;rsquo;s honestly a blast. Each track is so intimate yet powerful and does a great job at guiding you through this ode to the physical and metaphysical world. This album made me cry so much over the weeks, especially on the more dense tracks like &lt;code&gt;Mio cristo piange diamante&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Memória&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Berghain&lt;/code&gt; which for me personally have both a nihilist point of view and also a hopeful one for this relationship with the divine and our world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip for the Week #2: Improving native fuzzy finder in neovim</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/quick-tip-for-the-week-2-improving-native-fuzzy-finder-in-neovim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/quick-tip-for-the-week-2-improving-native-fuzzy-finder-in-neovim/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is a continuation to the original implementation, you can read at: &lt;a href="https://cherryramatis.xyz/posts/native-fuzzy-finder-in-neovim-with-lua-and-cool-bindings/"&gt;https://cherryramatis.xyz/posts/native-fuzzy-finder-in-neovim-with-lua-and-cool-bindings/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After using the native fuzzy finder implementation everyday for almost a month now I can safely say it&amp;rsquo;s quite great for my personal workflow, it works flawlessly and it&amp;rsquo;s simple enough so I can extend easily. One thing though that is a bit annoying is how often the popup window updates (it updates each time you press a character), sometimes that much update add some flickering to the popup re-rendering. Luckily &lt;a href="mailto:martini97@protonmail.ch"&gt;Alessandro&lt;/a&gt; contacted me with a better implementation that not only simplified a bit the code, but also added a debounce function to avoid that much update cycles.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip for the Week #2: Creating a simple wrapper around aider (AI assistant)</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/quick-tip-for-the-week-2-creating-a-simple-wrapper-around-aider/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/quick-tip-for-the-week-2-creating-a-simple-wrapper-around-aider/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not the biggest fan of AI usage while coding, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely changed the way we produce and thinkg about code, so I decided to give it a try and integrate into my workflow (tried copilot in the past and couldn&amp;rsquo;t get used to the AI completion popping off all the time). After some months testing I settle myself with a working workflow: Just a chat assistant opened close to my editor which I can either use as an alternative to modern search engines when the query is too complex or to maintain a persistent conversation about possible solutions. I&amp;rsquo;ve being quite happy with that setup so far as it keeps me in control of the code that it&amp;rsquo;s being shipped while also benefitting from that speed of using an LLM. For the chat integration I chose using the &lt;a href="https://aider.chat/"&gt;aider chat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip for the Week #1: Making Netrw More Usable</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/quick-tip-for-the-week-1-making-netrw-more-usable/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/quick-tip-for-the-week-1-making-netrw-more-usable/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely not new to any Neovim user that we have &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of file browser plugins, all over from the super minimalistic, like &lt;a href="https://github.com/justinmk/vim-dirvish"&gt;vim-dirvish,&lt;/a&gt; to the full-blown new experiences like &lt;a href="https://github.com/stevearc/oil.nvim"&gt;oil.nvim&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://github.com/nvim-neo-tree/neo-tree.nvim"&gt;neo-tree.nvim&lt;/a&gt;. But what about netrw? You know, that file browser that comes default with (Neo)Vim and certainly has some weird behaviors? Recently I started thinking about what could be done to fix some of those weird behaviors and potentially remove yet another plugin in my crusade for minimalism. As always, I hope you find something useful for your own config. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Native Fuzzy Finder in Neovim With Lua and Cool Bindings</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/native-fuzzy-finder-in-neovim-with-lua-and-cool-bindings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/native-fuzzy-finder-in-neovim-with-lua-and-cool-bindings/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I read a particular &lt;a href="https://yobibyte.github.io/vim.html"&gt;blog post by yobibyte&lt;/a&gt; about a no-plugins approach to Neovim configuration, which stuck with me. I started to think more and more about how much stuff I really need for my config to suit my needs. Personally, the main reason why I resonate so much with a particular family of editors (Vim, Nvim, Kakoune, Emacs, etc.) is the ability to add as much stuff as you want, but at the same time the opportunity to remove as much bloat as possible—a little controversial, but if you think about it, it&amp;rsquo;s the best scenario for customizability. I remember watching a video about the concept of a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QMVIJhC9Veg"&gt;PDE&lt;/a&gt; coined by a Neovim contributor called teej_dv, and it really stuck with me. These types of editors are more like an environment than just a product with a single goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title> (format t "Hello world~%")</title><link>//localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nice that you&amp;rsquo;re here! I&amp;rsquo;ll be trying to post both &lt;code&gt;personal&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tech&lt;/code&gt; related stuff, the idea is to keep me writing more constantly.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title/><link>//localhost:1313/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/86631177/212934124-15c3ef0a-9a48-4a00-af39-8e0d8a89c4f4.gif" alt="princess-bubble-gum-388429236"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(better description wip)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🔭 I’m currently working as a frontend developer @ iFood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💜 I&amp;rsquo;m a proud member of the best community &lt;a href="https://github.com/he4rt"&gt;He4rt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🤝 I love to write about ruby and other stuffs I&amp;rsquo;m using at &lt;a href="https://dev.to/cherryramatis/"&gt;Dev to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 Ask me about vim, emacs, automation, scripting, ruby, lisp, etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⚡ Fun fact I can type 118 words per minute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📫 How to reach me: &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/cherryramatis/"&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="mailto:cherry.ramatis&amp;#43;contact@gmail.com"&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🏳️‍⚧️ Pronouns: She/Her Ela/Dela&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🗣️ Languages that i speak: Brazilian Portuguese (Native) and English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>